Sahil Khose

(+91) 70573 70005 \Leftrightarrow sahilkhose18@gmail.com Website \Leftrightarrow LinkedIn \Leftrightarrow GitHub \Leftrightarrow Google Scholar

PROFILE

My research experience and interests are in the field of - Computer Vision, Continual Learning, Zero-Shot Learning, Semi-supervised Learning, NLP and Self-supervised Learning. Solving deep learning problems using a limited (ideally zero) amount of data is what piques my interest.

EDUCATION

Manipal Institute of Technology

2018-Present

B. Tech in Computer and Communication Engineering (Minor in Big Data)

CGPA: 8.49/10

EXPERIENCE

AI Research Assistant

July 2021 - Present

Artificial Intelligence and Robotics Lab (AIRL), IISc Bangalore

Bangalore, India

- Working on Continual Generalized Zero-Shot Learning(CGZSL) under Dr. Suresh Sundaram.
- Working on Sketch Based Image Retrieval and Instance Segmentation in a CGZSL setting.

AI Research Assistant

April 2021 - Present

Manipal Institute of Technology (Dr. Harish Kumar J.R.)

Manipal, India

- Developed a model for **fovea disc segmentation** using semi-supervised segmentation.
- Working on macular degeneration classification using multi-task deep learning.

AI Perception Developer

Feb 2019 - May 2021

Project MANAS

Manipal, India

- Worked on a AGV for the **27th Intelligent Ground Vehicle Competition** held in Michigan, USA.
- Worked on building a level 2-3 autonomy car on Indian roads for the Mahindra \$1Million Challenge.

Publications

BERT based Transformers lead the way in Extraction of Health Information from Social Media Published in proceedings of NAACL 2021 GitHub | aclweb Apr 2021

- ADE classification: Handled a 7% 93% class imbalance dataset. Trained RoBERTa and BioBERT. Achieved valid F1: 85% test F1: 61%. [Rank: 1] (ADE: Adverse Drug Effects)
- ADE span detection: RoBERTa based NER pipeline. Achieved valid F1: 54% test F1: 50%.[Rank: 2]
- COVID classification: RoBERTa, DeBERTa, Covid-Twitter BERT, BERTweet, and ensemble were trained for the 3 class classification problem. Achieved valid F1: 99% test F1: 94%. [Rank: 2]

Semi-Supervised Classification and Segmentation on High Resolution Aerial Images

Accepted at Tackling Climate Change with ML workshop at NeurIPS 2021 GitHub | arXiv | Blog | Demo May 2021

- Handled a dataset of 1450 images with just 25% labelled data and a class imbalance of 12.5% 77.5%.
- ResNet18 with our implemented semi-supervised pipeline fetched 96.70% test accuracy beating the best model of the FloodNet paper by a huge 3% margin with less than half the parameters.
- Implemented a semi-supervised multi-class segmentation pipeline for 10 class segmentation. DeepLabv3+ with a EfficientNet-B3 backbone fetched us 52.23% mIoU on the test set.

Extraction of Color Information from Images for Generation of Colored Outlines and Sketches Accepted at New in ML workshop at NeurIPS 2021 GitHub | arXiv | Demo Aug 2021

- Applied image processing techniques and unsupervised learning to quantize and extract colours in images and render sketches with coloured outlines.
- Used conditional GANs for image to coloured sketch generation with the help of colourspace manipulation.

A Studious Approach to Semi-Supervised Learning

Accepted at ICBINB workshop at NeurIPS 2021 GitHub | arXiv

- Performed **distillation** for **semi-supervised learning** producing better and smaller models for real-time deployment proving fewer the labels, the more this approach benefits from a smaller student network
- We experimented on: Efficient Net-b5, ResNet-18, and MobileNet-V3-Large to demonstrate the benefit of model compression on four label splits, highlighting the semi-supervised advantage and model optimization.

Age-Related Macular Degeneration using Semi-Supervised Learning

Submitting to IEEE TMI journal (Advisor: Dr. Harish Kumar JR)

Oct 2021

- Developed a semi-supervised segmentation pipeline to train on 484 images for fovea disc segmentation for opthamology diagnosis.
- Performed semi-supervised classification on a dataset of **627** datapoints. The task being age-related macular degeneration with an imbalance of **1:5:5**. Our proposed method surpasses most of the **SOTA results**.

PROJECTS

Self-Driving Car and AGV - Project MANAS GitLab

Feb 2019 - May 2021

• Successfully implemented Lane Detection, Speed Bump Detection, Driving Imitation System, Depth map generation using multiple cameras and LiDAR input using Deep Learning.

StackGAN for text to image generation GitHub

Oct 2020

• Implemented the **StackGAN** (2 stages GAN) architecture from scratch in PyTorch with enhanced BERT data representations for synthesizing photo-realistic bird images from their textual descriptions.

QANet for SQuAD 2.0 (Question-Answering) GitHub

Sep 2020

• Implemented the **QANet** architecture from scratch in PyTorch consisting exclusively of convolution and self-attention, achieving **13x** faster train & **9x** faster inference than the BIDAF model (previous SOTA).

Stock Prediction using Hyper Graphs GitHub

Aug 2020

• Developed a Hypergraph structured dataset and built a Hypergraph NN based architecture with **Hypergraph** CNN, BERT, LSTM and attention network for stock prediction of 500 stocks over time.

Neural Machine Translation GitHub | Demo

July 2020

• Built a Neural Machine Translation model using a seq2seq bi-LSTM architecture with attention and hybrid character-word level language modelling. Achieved **37 BLEU** on Spanish-English translation.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Project MANAS stood World Rank 1 at the 27th Intelligent Ground Vehicle Competition (IGVC 2019).
- IGVC Awards: Interoperability 1st, Design 2nd, Cybersecurity 3rd, Grand prize Lescoe Cup.
- Project MANAS won the Million Dollar Mahindra Rise Prize. (top 13 out of 153 teams in India).
- Led a team of 3 to secure an All India Rank 19 in the Flipkart GRiD 2.0 level 1.
- Led a team of 4 to secure Rank 1 in Google Hash Code 2020 in Manipal hub, ranked 500 in India.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, C++, Java, C

Tools and Libraries: PyTorch, NumPy, Tensorflow, OpenCV, Matplotlib

Experienced in: Computer Vision, NLP, Zero-Shot Learning, Semi-supervised learning, Distillation

Extracurricular

FruitPunch AI (AI expertise head)

Aug 2021 - Present

Leading the first chapter in India to organise AI for Good Challenges for nonprofits.

YouTube Channel (Online Educator)

June 2021 - Present

Conducts weekly presentations on cutting edge research papers in the field of AI.

Research Society Manipal (AI division mentor)

Nov 2020 - Present

Mentoring and guiding several students to pursue research in the field of Deep Learning.

NAACL reviewer Mar 2021

Reviewed multiple research papers as a part of the review committee for SMM4H Workshop.